now your soldiers are killing people in
сейчас э ваши Солдаты убивают людей в
my country And yours are killing
моей стране Так и ваши тоже убивают
ours too That's right Because ours
наших Правильно Потому что наши
are defending themselves And yours are attacking it turns out
защищаются А ваши нападают получается
yours are such poor unfortunates didn't
ваши такие бедные несчастные ничего не
do anything they just attacked you and that's it Well it turns out
делали на вас просто напали и всё Ну так
look you came to our
получается смотри вы же пришли к нам в
country with a war and why did it
страну с войной а из-за чего она
start Yes
началась Да подо из-за
why let's chat I'm not arguing
чего Давайте пообщаемся Я не ссорюсь
and you are streaming No but I'm not arguing
а вы Стрим ведёте Нет но я не ссорюсь
you are 18 years old
вам 18 лет
I am from the city of Khmelnitsky And where are you from
есть Я из города Хмельницке А вы
Stavropol Stavropol Yes my father is from
Ставрополя Ставрополь Да у меня отец из
Mineralnye Vody I come from there it
Минеральных Вод Родом это это там
turns out not far from there Yes I understand You are from
получается недалеко чи два Да Поня Вы из
Stavropol itself or from the Stavropol
самого Ставрополя или из Ставропольского
Territory I
края
understand what you work as you
понял кем работаете кем
study to be a speech therapist we study as teachers we
учитесь на логопеда учимся учителями
work great not a speech therapist This is a very
работаем классно не логопед Это очень
good but hard
хороший но тяжёлая
job let's say and why did you choose
работа а а почему выбрали именно
this one just like that do you have any children do you
такое просто так детей лю у вас кто-то
know at
из знакомых есть на
war
войне
Yes
Да
father uncle
отец дядя
alive
живой
Yes And how did he get to the
Да А как он попал на
war well mobilization damn it's been 3 years
войну ну мобилизация блин это уже 3 года
he's been
он
there well yes but he  he arrived he was wounded he had an
там ну да но он приехал у него ранения
operation they did it and
были операцию емы сделали и обратно
sent him back Where is he and how did they send him
отправили А куда он и как его отправили
if he was
если он
wounded Well, like they did an operation he
раненный Ну типа сделали операцию он
recovered and sent him back
восстановился и обратно отправили скуда
Where where was he wounded
куда он был раненый
with his legs something happened he was sent to run with a wounded leg Well,
с ногами что-то было его с раненой ногой
no, well they did an operation on him And
отправили бегать Ну нет ну ему операцию
he lay at home and
сделали А он отлежал дома и его
sent him back some kind of horror And at least they
отправили обратно ужас какой-то А хоть
paid for the
выплатили за
injury I don’t know probably Damn it’s awful And
ранение не знаю наверное Блин жесть а
what does the aunt say she’s worried Well, yes, she’ll
что тётя говорит переживает Ну да она
go there too they’ll be close by so that they can
туда поедет тоже рядышком будет чтоб
love each other there and where to just
там любить друг друга да где просто
wait
ждать
Well, like What do you think about this war in general
Ну типа А вы как относитесь вообще к
negatively And what do you think is the reason for it Well,
негативно А как думаете из-за чего
because of the different political
она Ну из-за разных политических
views of
взглядов
our supreme people, for example
наших верховных людей например
Well, to be honest, we don’t really understand
Ну мы если честно не очень разбираемся в
this topic and it seems to me that this topic is
этой теме и мне кажется то что эта тема
not for discussion at all, that is, we don’t
вообще не для обсуждения то есть мы не
know
знаем
zeros and somehow it’s very stupid to talk about it
нолики и как-то рассуждать об этом очень
because you see your side
глупо потому что вы видите свою сторону
we see our side the point in talking about it is
мы видим свою сторону смысл об этом
not the fact that we are not politicians
не дело в том что мы не политики
Well, as if I were a simple person and I’m
Да как бы я простой человек и мне
interested in talking with ordinary people
интересно с простыми людьми
that all are simple  people suffer
поговорить что все простые люди страдают
what on the one hand what on the
что с одной стороны Что с
other Just there are those who understand
другой Просто есть те которые понимают
this there are those who
это есть те которые
and how can we change what we can And
а как мы можем изменить что мы можем А
what can we what can we we can wait
что мы можем что мы можем мы можем ждать
and that's it Well
и
if we wait like that then they
всё Ну так если так ждать так и дядю
can
могут
kill your uncle Well I understand that they can Well what are we going to
убить Ну я понимаю что могут Ну а что мы
do it's just if if what in
сделаем это просто если если что в
modern society in principle you can
современном обществе в принципе можно
walk down the street and you can be drunk just
идти по улице и тебя могут упить просто
for the fact that you are walking therefore it
за то то что ты идёшь поэтому как бы мне
seems to me that the treatment is not a sign to jump just in
кажется лече не знак на прыгнуть чтобы
case Yes what someone you
на всякий случай Да что кто-то тебе
damn someone lives on and acquaintances like this
блин кто-то живёт на а знакомых вот так
your friends some friends friends
у ваших друзей каких-то друзей друзей
have a lot of such who died in your
много есть таких кто погибли в вашем
city Yes Yes damn And what do they die for it
городе Да Да блин А за что они погибают
turns out for Russia for their country Well to
получается за Россию за свою страну Ну
me Well it seems to me that there are more for the
мне Ну мне кажется там больше идёт за
family That's because in fact there are a
семью Вот потому что на самом деле очень
lot of Volunteers from all sides
много Добровольцев со всех сторон
who go for the money as if this has been
которые идут ради денег как бы это
clear to everyone for a long time They understand what they are
понятно всем давно Они понимают чем они
risking therefore it seems to me that this is
рискуют поэтому мне кажется что это уже
actually their choice but it is simply not clear
собственно их выбор а просто непонятно
why by the way Panther You have a cool one
почему кстати Пантер Прикольная у тебя
Thank you
Спасибо
very much did you draw this yourself or did you buy it
большое это сама рисовала или это купила
like this no it's on a T-shirt Print
такой нет это на футболке прин Принт
got it By the way it turns out here like uh
понял Кстати вот получается тут как ээ
if Russia I was wondering if there
если у России Вот мне интересно было
is oil gas diamonds gold it is like
есть нефть газ алмазы золото она типа
rich Yes why is it that
богатая Да почему так получается что
people live in poverty that they are forced to
люди живут бедно что они вынуждены
earn money by war
зарабатывать войной
Well look
Ну смотрите
like it depends on the people themselves
типа это зависит от самих людей
some make millions some
некоторые делают миллионы некоторые
want to earn a hundred just by working in a
хотят будучи работая просто в
supermarket that is It
супермаркете зарабатывают сотку то есть
already depends on the person like what
Это уже зависит от человека типа к чему
he strives for So accordingly if a
он стремится Вот соответственно если
person without any education without
человек без какого-то образования без
any goals in life he will find a way to
каких-то целей в жизни он найдёт способ
earn easy money being this with
заработать лёгкие деньги будучи это с
or being these are just simple bookmarks there are a
либо будучи это просто простые закладки
lot of different countries that are like
очень много разных стран которые типа
so rich and everywhere there can be people who are
такие богатые и везде могут найтись люди
poor because someone does not
которые бедные потому что кто-то не
strive for someone It's just that I don't know
стремится кому-то Просто там я не знаю
initially there was no luck and so on there
изначально не повезло и так далее разные
are different situations It seems to me that in all
бывают ситуации Мне кажется во всех
countries there are both rich and poor
странах есть что и богатые что и бедные
Neva What kind of Independence yes that is
Нева Какая Независимости да то есть
Russia is rich but Russia is not a bond there
Россия богата но Россия это несть уз у
is water We do not suffer from this about something
есть вода Мы из этого не
else we are talking about the fact that there are
страдаем про другое речь идёт то что там
some people who are poor Yes it seems to me
некоторые люди бедные Да мне кажется
everywhere Yes there are rich in Ukraine
везде Да есть в Украине есть богатые
how much is your salary Well in different ways
сколько зарплаты у вас Ну по-разному
well for example well the average salary How much is
ну например ну средняя зарплата Сколько
50 probably Well the average salary Yes
50 наверное Ну средняя зарплата Да
50.000  I
50.000
understand how much you would like to
понял вы сколько хотели бы
receive interesting just to have
получать интересные просто чтобы на всё
enough for everything in principle enough
хватало в принципе хватит
to live and not deny yourself anything Well,
чтобы жить и ни в чём себе не отказывать
how much How much is needed for this
Ну сколько Сколько для этого
I don’t know It seems to each
нужно я не знаю Мне кажется у каждого
person is different I can’t
человека разные я допустим не могу
answer this
сейчас ответить на этот
question now Yes What do you think because of this
вопрос да Как вы считаете из-за этой
war that many Russian men
войны то что много российских мужчин
died how will someone replace them in
погибло как кто будет заменять их на
all these
этих всех
jobs Well, in fact, now other
работах ну вообще-то сейчас другие
men are born and grow up therefore Well,
мужчины рождаются растут поэтому Ну как
like, yes, if a forty-year-old man died there, yes, so that
бы да вот если умер там сорокалетний
he would be replaced by a newborn
мужик да чтобы его заменил новорожденный
Yes, it would take 40 years, as it were, to pass
Да нужно чтобы 40 лет как бы прошло
True Well, now Well, it seems to me that this is
Правда Ну сейчас Ну мне кажется это
a bit narrow thinking During the Great
немного узкое мышление во время Великой
Patriotic War, exactly the same number of men
Отечественной войны точно также мужчин
died, but at the same time, the country somehow
погибло но при этом как бы страна как-то
developed and it developed in principle and
развивалась и она развилась в принципе и
somehow think about who will replace It
как-то думать о том что кто заменит Мне
seems to me that at that time no one thought about this who was
кажется то что в то время об этом никто
replacing whom Well And now But by
не думал кто кого заменяет Ну А сечас А
the way, if like new men
вот кстати если типа новые мужчины
are born Yes, if these men died yes, then
рождаются Да если эти мужчины погибли да
from whom are new men born Well,
то от кого рождаются новые
not all Men are men, yes
мужчины Ну не все же Мужчины же мужчи да
Well, look, for example, in society there are
Ну смотри например вот в обществе
approximately the same number of
приблизительно одинаковое количество
men and women Yes, there were 100 men  100
мужчин женщин Да вот было 100 мужчин 100
women Yes, if 50 men died,
женщин Да если 50 мужчин погибло
there were 100 women left
осталось 100 женщин 50 мужчин от кого
50 men who will give birth to 50 women It is clear from these men And the
родят 50 женщин Понятно от этих мужчин А
other 50 women who will give birth to what
другие 50 женщин от кого родят то что
now some men are
сейчас некоторые мужчины
just bucks who, excuse me of course for the
просто баки которые извиняюсь конечно за
expression, who simply impregnate
выражение которые просто оплодотворяют
women That is, not all men are exemplary like this, like
женщин То есть Не все мужчины примерные
I have one woman,
такие типа вот у меня есть одна женщина
that's all I will have, so I
всё она у меня будет одна поэтому я
think it seems to me that there will be
думаю мне кажется найдутся точно так
others just like that If the
остальных п Если до такой ситуации
country gets to such a situation, which I am very
дойдёт страна в чём я очень сильно не
unsure of, then these 50 men will
уверена то эти 50 мужчин будут
impregnate 100 women and then there, and 100
оплодотворять 100 женщин и то там а 100
women is not a 100% option that all 100
женщин это не 100% вариант что все 100
women will give birth, right, there is some percentage that
женщин родят правильно есть процент
some are infertile
какой-то то что некоторые бесплодные
or have some genetic diseases
либо какие-то генетические заболевания
So maybe out of 100 women there are only
Так что может быть на 100 женщин только
50 healthy And out of 50 men there are only 30
50 здоровых А на 50 мужчин только 30
healthy or 20 This is the Supreme Court, what are you
здоровых или 20 это ВС стати что
writing down? The
записываете
situation is that people are
яново ситуация люди
dying, yes But it turns out that here it was not
погибают да Но получается тут просто не
we who attacked Russia, yes, Russia
мы же напали на Россию да Россия на нас
attacked us if Russia  stop and withdraw
напала если Россия остановится и выведет
troops and there will be no war and no one
войска и не будет войны и у нас никто не
will die here I
будет погибать тут всё
simply don't agree with this And what exactly do you
просто не согласна с этим А с чем именно
disagree with well with the fact that
согласны ну с тем
firstly I think that Russia is
что во-первых я считаю то что Россия
still trying to defend itself and simply
всё-таки старается обороняться и просто
not let anyone near its borders this is the
не подпускать к своим границам это
first and secondly the president you have
первое а второе президент который у вас
now he is a little this and in the sense of
сейчас он немножко это а в смысле
defending itself and not letting anyone near its
обороняться и не подпускать к своим
borders if Russia entered the territory of
границам если Россия зашла на территорию
Ukraine on the contrary
Украины наоборот
Well the one who is stronger is the one who hits What to do
Ну тот кто сильнее тот и бьёт Что
Russia is still hitting and attacking
сделать то Россия всё-таки бьёт нападает
or it is not letting anyone near its borders I am
или она не подпускает к своим границам Я
confused it is not letting anyone near
запутался не подпускает так как она не
its borders if it
подпускает к своим границам если она аж
was as far as Kyiv Well that's how it is
в Киев была
not letting anyone near it is
залезла Ну вот так вот не подпускает
expanding only
расширяется только
we cannot judge everyone has their own opinion
мы не можем судить у каждого своё мнение
If you really want to just
Если вы хотите действительно просто
talk then we can talk about
поговорить то можем поговорить о
something else And now you are just
чём-нибудь другом А сейчас вы просто
asking leading questions to provoke
задаёте наводящие вопросы чтобы вызвать
either aggression or just to
либо агрессию либо просто там какую-то
collect some information from the outside or to collect views on someone or to collect
информацию набрать со стороны либо в кто
views on TikTok we treat it as if
просмотров набрать мы относимся как бы
neutral if they somehow accelerate on us
нейтрально если на нас как-то газуют
naturally we will defend our
естественно мы будем защищать свою
homeland and if we just talk then everything is just
родину а если просто поговорить то всё
talk We are all
просто поговорить Все мы
people there is no such thing as a bad
люди нету какой-то там плохой
nationality or a bad people there are
национальности или плохого народа есть
just some bad people they are
просто какие-то плохие люди они есть
everywhere And what do you think Ukraine is to blame for the fact that
везде А как вы считаете Украина виновата
Russia attacked
в том что Россия напала на
it I can’t answer this question I don’t
неё не могу ответить на этот вопрос я не
fully know the whole
знаю полностью всей
situation and Ukraine also doesn’t
ситуации и Украина тоже не знает
fully know all the situations if anything no one
полностью все ситуации если что никто не
T the whole situation the only thing I
Т поть всей ситуации единственное Я
think is that yes Russia will win in any
считаю то что да Россия победит в любом
case and why will it win Well because it is Russia
случае а почему она победит Ну потому
Well in the sense because it is
что это Россия Ну в смыс потому что это
Russia the
Россия
argument is because I believe in my homeland in
аргумент потому что я верю в свою родину
my country in my
в свою страну в своих
people in my
людей в своего
president I am kind of proud of it that’s
президента я как бы горда
all everywhere there are some bad moments
всё везде бывают какие-то плохие моменты
and moments that people are unhappy with but I
и моменты которым недоволен народ но я
think that everything will be fine that’s
считаю то что как бы всё будет нормально
all And if you don’t like something
вот и всё А если что-то не понравится
Any person can move
Любой человек может переехать
somewhere get a
куда-нибудь
new citizenship there
сделать себе там новое гражданство
change your
изменить свою
life each person chooses for himself That’s
жизнь каждый человек сам выбирает Вот и
all Where have you been
всё Где вы были за
abroad nowhere nowhere And
границей нигде нигде А
why Well because
почему Ну потому
why haven’t you been Well we are 21 years old that
что ну почему не были Ну нам 21 год то
is we don’t work We study  like
есть мы не работаем Мы учимся как бы ну
okay we work we study Yeah, keep in mind
ладно работаем учимся Да ну Имей в виду
maybe with their parents some
там может с родителями там некоторые
go abroad sometimes there or by themselves
ездят там за границу бывает там или сами
18-20 years old Well why is it that you have
там 18-20 лет Ну почему так вы ни с
n't been abroad with your parents or by yourself yet
родителями ни с сами до сих пор не
because of what Well there
побывали за границей из-за чего Ну не
was no opportunity that is there is no money for the
было возможности а то есть нету денег на
trip No my dad is a military man he can't
поездку Нет у меня папа военный он не
travel we can't travel as a family dad is a military man but uncle is
выездной мы не можем семьёй выезжать
fighting Well dad is a
воюет Ну а папа
military man dad is not fighting I don't understand No he's not
военный папа не воюет не понял Нет он не
fighting He serves And where is the
воюет Он служит А где Какая
difference it's not fighting serves Well it's not sluzh it's
разни это не воюет служит Ну не слу это
just military sh to say that is to work
просто военны ш сказать то есть работат
from 8 to 6 conditionally like an ordinary one in the
с 8 до 6 условно как обычный ж
Russian Federation progo vo
Российской Федерации прого во
u it's
у
voluntary adj said that I want to
добровольно прил сказал что я хочу
defend the Motherland Armed Forces wait uncle mobile
защищать Родину ВС подожди дядя мобили
Zro or uncle
Зро или дядя
volunteer during mobilization it was possible to
доброволец во время мобилизации можно
come went on a
прийти пошл на
contract Why are you asking such questions
контракт Почему вы такие вопросы задаёте
because he is not a volunteer and
потому что он не доброволец й
nezi tevo
нези тево
con I understand so he can
конт понимаю так он может во время
say during mobilization Like I'm ready and that's all
мобилизации сказать Типа я готов и всё
fact he mobile
по факту он мобили
Zro understood and dad it turns out he is who there
Зро понял а папа получается он кто там
machine gunner plane Who is he I don't know about these
автоматчик самолёт Кто он Я в этих не
I don't know either I know that
шарю не знаю Я тоже не шарю Я знаю что
dad is a soldier and everything is terrible maybe this is her
папа военный и всё капец может это у неё
Legend for
Легенда такая для
mom Yeah Yeah
мамы Угу Да
definitely for fun he
обязательно по приколу военную форму
bought himself a military uniform every evening
себе купил каждый вечер приезжает
and he himself goes to his mistress
а сам к любовнице
100%
100%
understood But what do you think now in
понял А вот Как вы считаете сейчас в
Russia a lot of non-Russians come
России очень много нерусских приезжает
how do you feel about this
как вы к этому
generally
относитесь вообще
normally marry a
нормально выйдите замуж за
Tajik I'm dating a
таджика Я встречаюсь
zhim Well
жим
here's the question from whom will those
Ну вот и вопрос от кого будут ржать те
girls laugh like whose boys yes
девочки типа у которых мальчики да
died on their own from a Tajik my boy
погибли на сво от таджика у меня мальчик
didn't die on his own Well I mean that
не погиб на сво Ну я имею в виду что
someone look you could date
кто-то смотри ты могла бы встречаться с
some Russian boy and he died on his own That's
мальчиком каким-то русским а он погиб на
why you date a
сво Поэтому ты встречаешься с
Tajik Well yeah yeah That's the only reason damn it's not
таджиком Ну да да Только поэтому блин не
cool that is such a
прикольно получается то есть такое
substitution And how did you meet this
замещение А как ты познакомилась с
Tajik you
таджиком
studied in the same class
этим в одном классе училась
cool like now you live in the same
прикольно типа сейчас Вы живёте в одном
city
городе
Yes Cool and how  he has a Tajik name
Да Классно а как у него таджикское имя
here What are the names of Tajiks They do
вот Какие имена у таджиков Они же на
n't
наши не
look like ours It looks like Akhmed Oh yeah, well, it
похожи похоже Ахмед А да а ну на русский
looks like Russian Yes It looks like
да Похоже
Akhmed Yes, I have sko You are streaming No, to be
Ахмед Да у меня ско вы ведёте Стрим Нет
honest Well, we just
честно говорю Ну просто мы се всё равно
talked anyway You can already admit I am not
говорили Можете уже признаться не веду
streaming, I am just chatting I go out to chat in
Стрим просто общаюсь Я выхожу в чат в
the summer And why are you chatting, I am collecting
летку А для чего вы общаетесь набираю
information or what I am interested in Look, I am
информацию или что мне интересно Смотри
worried about the war, and we have I
я переживаю да о войне а у нас идут Я не
cannot ask Putin Zelensky a question Yes,
могу задать вопрос Путину зеленскому Да
but I can talk to ordinary people
но я могу пообщаться с простыми людьми
from Russia Yes, I go out like this and in the evening
из России Да я вот так выхожу и вечером
someone here swears, someone
кто-то тут матерится кто-то нормально
speaks normally Toto who are you normal
говорит Тото кто вот так вы нормальные
people Yes, that is, I am interested in understanding what
люди да то есть мне интересно понять как
Russians think, do they support the
думают россияне поддерживают ли они
war Why do they support it, and
войну Зачем поддерживают вот а вы
of course you do not support it, I do
поддерживаете конечно нет я ж
not Well, it seems to me that no one supports it, it is
не Ну мне кажется никто не поддерживает
just like everyone is on the side of their own
просто как бы каждый на стороне своей
country Here But all the same, some
страны Вот Но всё равно некоторых
citizens of, like, Russia and citizens of Ukraine,
граждан как бы России и граждан Украины
that is, there are citizens of Russia who are
то есть есть граждане России которые
like, they all need to be dragged, there are
типа вот их надо всех переть есть
citizens of Ukraine who say exactly the same thing
граждане Украины которые точно так же
here Well, your girlfriend
говорит вот Ну вот ваша ж подружка
supports it  war against Ukraine
поддерживает войну против Украины
she supports her country that is in
она поддерживает свою страну то есть в
any case she Nera supports yes
любом случае она Нера поддерживает да
supports the war against Ukraine Yes I
поддерживает войну против Украины Да я
support my country which is fighting
поддерживаю свою страны которая воюет
against Ukraine you will go to war against
против Украины ты пойдешь войну против
Ukraine Yes you are saying different things That is
Украины Да вы говорите разные вещи То
in any case she wants the
есть она же хочет в любом случае чтобы
war to end So she does not
закончилась война Значит она не
support I understand Yes I understood that is I
поддерживает понял Да я понял то есть я
understand correctly that means look she does not
правильно понимаю значит смотри она не
support the war against Ukraine But
поддерживает войну против Украины Но
since Russia is now fighting against
поскольку Россия сейчас воюет против
Ukraine And Russia is her country she
Украины А Россия её страна она
supports Russia in the war against
поддерживает Россию в войне против
Ukraine Of course I think that if
Украины Конечно я думаю то что если бы
your Ukraine were fighting there on someone's
ваша Украина воевала там на чьей-то
territory You would support
территории Вы точно так же поддерживаете
your country in the same way once again you heard me correctly
свою страну ещё раз ты правильно меня
Yes I understood correctly that she does not
услышала Да я правильно понял что она не
support the war against Ukraine But
поддерживает войну против Украины Но
since her country Russia is fighting against Ukraine And since it is
поскольку её страна Россия воюет против
her country she
Украины А раз это её страна она
supports Russia then she supports
поддерживает Россию то она поддерживает
Russia in the war against Ukraine it turns out
Россию в войне против Украины получается
I do not support and the concept itself I do not
я не поддерживаю а саму концепцию я не
support the war but my homeland Yes
поддерживаю войну но свою родину Да
why don't
почему
I walk down the street and say that yes
я не хожу по улице и не говорю то что да
everyone there no wait I just don't
там всех да не подожди я просто не
understand how it works in your head
понимаю как это у тебя работает в голове
you do not support the war but you
ты не поддерживаешь войну но ты
support the actions of Russia which is
поддерживаешь действия России которая
waging a war because it is your
ведёт войну потому что она твоя
homeland it supports  a soldier who is
родина она поддерживает солдат который
fighting there Yes, she does not support the war,
там воюют Да она не поддерживает войну
she supports the soldiers who are fighting in the
она поддерживает солдат который воюет на
war
войне
Yes, I collect dry rations for them, we
Да я собираю для них сух пойки мы это
manage all of this, that is, you do not
всё управляем о всё То есть ты не
support the war You just collect
поддерживаешь войну Ты просто собираешь
dry rations for the
сухпайки для
soldiers Well, why should they starve there Yes, I
солдат Ну а что им голодать там Да
really understood, I understood, that is, you
реально понял понял то есть ты
support the war
поддерживаешь войну
directly, I mean directly, but you support the
прямо в смысле прямо но ты поддерживаешь
army that is waging war Well, I support my
армию которая ведёт войну ну я
army, my Motherland
поддерживаю свою армию своей Родины
Why, yes, that is, Well, what am I
Почему да то есть Ну так я че проти
against, I am speechless I say, you support the war Well,
немею Я говорю ты поддерживаешь войну ну
you, I don’t know But put such a strong
ты ты я не знаю А так сильно делайте
emphasis on the fact that you
акцент на том что ты поддерживаешь войну
support the war Why Well, yes, that’s how it is I just can’t Are you somehow ashamed to admit to yourself that you support the war, you start it
что ты поддерживаешь войну ты начинаешь
I don’t support the war I just
я не поддерживаю войну Я просто
support my
поддерживаю своих
soldiers I don’t want there to be a war if there were
солдат Я не хочу чтобы была война если
none It would be great, but if
бы её не было Было бы классно но если
such a situation developed I am for my
такая ситуация сложилась Я за свою
Motherland, that is, if someone reproaches me,
Родину то есть если что-то упрёк мо в
I will say something like, what are you
кто-то скажет я скажу типа ты что что ли
doing? That’s all I understand, that is, let’s do it
Вот и всё Поня то есть а давай
this way if your Motherland  Let there be people in
так если твоя родина Да будет людей в
gas chambers You will support
газовых камерах ты будешь поддерживать
your
свою
homeland Why will it do this I don’t
родину Для чего она будет это делать не
know, but if it wants something to
знаю вот как захочет что-то там
happen there, in order to secure
случилось для того чтобы обезопасить
its borders, you will support your
свои границы будешь поддерживать свою
country Well, this
страну Ну это
But this is
Но это
strange Imagine For example, if Putin
странно Представь Например если Путин
issues a decree to
выдаст указ в целях безопасности
destroy the entire male population of Ukraine for security purposes,
уничтожить всё мужское население Украины
you will support your homeland in
ты будешь поддерживать свою родину в
this I will not care at all, to be
этом мне вообще будет всё равно если
honest, no, I don’t care about this
честно нене я вот этой
girlfriend I don’t understand the
подружки Я не понимаю
question Look, if for the security of
вопрос смотри если для безопасности
Russia, Putin says for the security of
России вот скажет Путин для безопасности
Russia because in Ukraine men are
России потому что в Украине мужчин
recruited into the army, it is necessary to destroy the entire
набирают в армию нужно уничтожить всё
male population of Ukraine
мужское население Украины
and your soldiers will destroy the entire
и ваши солдаты будут уничтожать всё
male population of Ukraine You will
мужское население Украины ты будешь
support your homeland in
поддерживать свою родину в
this I cannot answer Well, this still makes no
этом я не могу ответить Ну этоже ещё нет
sense Zelensky will issue such a decree
смысла Зеленский выдаст такою касу
now, now your soldiers are killing people
сейчас сейчас ваши Солдаты убивают людей
in my country And yours are also killing
в моей стране Так и ваши тоже убивают
ours That’s right Because ours are
наших Правильно Потому что наши
defending themselves, yours are attacking, it turns out that yours are
защищаются ваши нападают получается ваши
such poor unfortunates, they did nothing, they
такие бедные несчастные ничего не делали
just attacked you and that’s it Well, it turns
на вас просто напали и всё Ну так
out that look, you came to our
получается смотри вы же пришли к нам в
country with a war, but why did it
страну с войной а из-за чего она
start? Because of what?
началась по из-за
Because of what  look you are now
Чего из-за чего смотрите вы сейчас
talking about the fact that there is like Russia
говорите О том то что там типа Россия
attacked your soldiers are defending themselves but this is
напала ваши Солдаты защищается Но это
happening in the present tense you don't
происходит в настоящем времени вы же не
know what would have happened in the future tense that is it would have been
знаете что было бы в будущем времени То
possible yes that is look
есть можно было бы да то есть Смотри вот
this is what was you can fantasize as
это что было можно фантазировать
much as you want look Russia attacked
угодно смотри Россия напала на
Ukraine Yes you are the occupiers destroying you
Украину Да вы оккупанты вас уничтожают
this is all
это всё
clearly for what Napa you are saying that this is why
чётко за что Напа ты говоришь что Вот за
Russia attacked Ukraine I asked for
что напала Россия на Украину Я спросила
what you know I don't
за что вы знаете я не
know For nothing attacked Just like that Just like that
знаю Ни за что напала Просто так Просто
no well
не ну
point it out Poli and I am walking I wanted to
наставь Поли а я иду мне захотелось
break your nose and I hit Polo's nose
поломать тебе нос и Я ударил поло нос за
why did I break your nose Okay now And look
что я тебе нос Хорошо сейчас А смотрите
why then and since 2014 Ukraine has been beating its
А почему тогда а с 2014 года Украина
own Why like that in 14 I
своих же била Почему так в 14 я же
look you didn't understand I am asking you
смотри ты Не понял Я же тебя спрашиваю
why Russia attacked Ukraine in 14
зачем Россия в 14м году напала на
Crimea Donetsk Lugansk in
Украину Крым Донецк Луганск в
2014 Russia captured Crimea
четырнадцатом году Россия захватила Крым
Donetsk and Lugansk this is a fact already look already
Донецк и Луганск это факт уже смотри уже
and in he recognized and in all who recognized
и в он признали и в бсе всё кто признал
Russia admitted
Росси призна
Yes, yes, we were in Crimea Our
сказал Да что Да мы были в Крыму Наши
troops, yes, said that they were in Donetsk and Lugansk
войска да сказали что в Донецке Луганске
Putin already admitted it last
были Путин уже признал ещё в прошлом
year when they annexed it to new
году когда присоединили э в новые
regions in the Constitution, he said Yes, they were
регионы в Конституцию он сказал Да они
defending their own No, so look what you
своих же защищали нет так смотри что ты
come up with Putin, look at the OSCE report Yes,
придумаешь Путин посмотри отчёт обсе Да
Putin spoke at the UN and said we
Путин в ООН выступал и говорил мы
consider these territories ours We have been
считаем эти территории своими мы с
fighting for them since 2014 That's all he
четырнадцатого года за них воюем всё он
said, [ __ ], it's the residents of Donetsk,
сказал сри именно жители Донецка
Lugansk and Crimea who would have been for the fact that there
Луганска и Крыма были бы за то то что
really was a war and Russia attacked
реально была война и Россия напала на
these Republics The residents of Crimea, Donetsk and
эти Республики жители бы Крыма Донецк и
Lugansk would not have been happy that they are
луганс не радовались бы то что они
Russia That's exactly what they are not happy about The thing is,
Россия Вот именно они и не радуются Дело
look, I'll explain in your
в том что смотри у вас объясню в вашем
city Yes, in Stavropol You can go
городе Да в Ставрополе Вы можете выйти
to a rally against the government and we will not go
на митинг против власти а мы не будем
out What's the point for us to go out Well, for
выходить Смысл нам выходить Ну вот
example, what will happen to you If you
например что будет с вами Если вы
go out with a poster against Putin Yes,
выйдете с плакатом против Путина Да
10 days Sim That's it, look, you are in
суток 10 Сим Вот вот вот смотри ты в
Stavropol If you go out with a poster
Ставрополе Если выйдешь с плакатом
simply against Putin, you will be at least
просто против Путина тебя как минимум на
10 days will be taken now the question What will happen
10 суток возьмут теперь вопрос Что будет
in Donetsk to a person who comes out with a
в Донецке с человеком который выйдет с
poster against
плакатом против
Putin this is just nonsense you say
Путина вот это вы просто бред Говорите
Na I ask Look are you
На я спрашиваю Смотри ты в Ставрополе
afraid to come out with a poster against Putin in Stavropol Do
боишься выйти с плакатом против Путина
you understand that you will be put on a bottle for
Ты понимаешь что тебя тебя на бутыля на
10 days I ask the question What will happen in
10 суток я задаю вопрос Что будет в
Donetsk where there are a lot of weapons
Донецке где куча оружи
lawlessness army Yes Russian with a
беспредела армия Да Российская с
person who comes out with a poster
человеком который выйдет с плакатом
against Putin what will happen just
против Путина что будет просто
tell me You answered this question yourself
скажи Вы сами ответили на этот вопрос
If that
Если
person will simply be thrown into the basement like
что человека просто кинут на подвал как
everyone was thrown Yes of course and that's how it was
и кидали всех Да конечно и так и было
look look deputy from the city of
посмотри посмотри депутат из города
Gorlovka Yes Rybak they killed him for
Горловка Да Рыбак убили его за то что
raising the Ukrainian
поднял украинский
flag now one on Google Yes Rybak
флаг сейчас одна на Гугле Да Рыбак
deputy Rybak Gorlovka look Yes
депутат Рыбак Горловка посмотри Да на
I'm interested that there are people in Crimea in
мне интересно вот то есть люди в Крыму в
Donetsk in Lugansk Yes they can't
Донецке в Луганске Да они не могут
say anything against Russia for Ukraine
ничего сказать против России за Украину
because immediately them Yes of course they
потому что сразу их Да конечно
showed how they rejoiced and
показывали как они радовались и
showed how they gave up when your
показывали как они сдали когда ваших
own were beaten right look I
своих же и били правильно смотри я ещё
Look again I'm telling you that now if
раз смотри я тебе говорю что сейчас если
they come to your university and say Now the
вам в университет придут и скажут Сейчас
president will come Yes none of you will
приедет президент да Вам никто из вас
ask him a bad question Yes everyone
плохого вопроса ему не задаст Да все
will clap True, your whole group will be
будут хлопать правда вот вас всю группу
put in jail and you will clap for
посадят и вы будете хлопать президенту
your president You will be afraid that your
своему вы будете бояться что-то вам
supervisor will tell you something Someone will say something
куратор скажет кто-то что-то скажет
bad And you will not say anything bad
плохое И вы ничего плохого не скажете
Also spark bu Also here people who are
также искре бу также и тут люди которые
there Look people who are in Donetsk in
там смотри люди которые в Донецке в
Lugansk Yes they can't approach them
Луганске Да они не могут их подходят
Skat you support Russia If they
Скат вы поддерживаете Россию если они
say on camera that they don't support Yes
ска на камеру что не поддерживают да
immediately trumpet that here is an Agent of Ukraine and that's it
сразу раструб что вот Агент Украины и
He will be screwed That's all it's simple
всё Ему капец будет Вот и всё всё просто
It was like in Kherson Look Russia
это было как в Херсоне смотри Россия
drew that there was a referendum in Kherson that
нарисовала что в Херсоне референдум что
everyone is for Russia When Russian troops
все за Россию когда российские войска
fled from Kherson Ukraine returned all the
убежали из Херсона Украина вернулась все
people came out And what did they say like we were under
люди вышли И что сказали типа мы были в
occupation we were silent because we
оккупации мы молчали потому что мы
couldn't do anything Yes Because
ничего не могли сделать да Потому что
here they killed everyone who would say that they are for
тут убивали всех кто скажет что они за
Ukraine and everything and they live normally Now
Украину и всё и нормально живут Теперь
everyone is happy about Ukraine I also
всё радуется Украине также
understand you were among these people I'm
понимаю вы были среди этих людей
right  look I'm from Donetsk myself
правильно я смотри я сам из Донецка родо
If you're interested you want to say Yes I
Если тебе интересно хочеш сказать Да я
lived in Donetsk until 2016 in 2014
до 2016 года жил в Донецке в 2014 году
when these Russian
когда начались российские вот эти
invasions into the Donetsk region began I lived there I would have
вторжения в донецкую область я там жил я
left immediately in 2014 Yes but my
уехал бы ещё сразу в 2014 Да но у меня
mother there is old she didn't want to
мама там старенькая она не хотела
leave I only persuaded her in 2016 so that
уезжать Я её только в шестнадцатом году
we could leave she didn't want to
уговорил чтобы мы уехали она не хотела
because she has a house Here is a vegetable garden she
потому что у неё домик Вот огородик она
says I've lived here all my life since
говорит я всю жизнь Тут прожила вот
2014 I remember I
четырнадцатого года Я помню у меня
had a classmate Sanya Prokhorov you know
Одноклассник был Саня Прохоров знаешь
what happened to him
что с ним
so on April 12 Yes
случилось так вот 12 апреля Да
2014 when Russian
четырнадцатого года когда российские
troops entered Yes into the city of Donetsk Yes he
войска зашли Да в город Донецк Да он
came out with a Ukrainian
вышел с украинским
flag you know what they did to him what they
флагом знаешь что с ним сделали что с
did to him they
сделали
killed Well why was it necessary to
убили Ну зачем надо было с флагом
go out with a flag I mean he was in Ukraine with a
выходить в смысле он в Украине с
Ukrainian flag yes And then
украинским флагом да А тут пришли
Russian troops came a man came out with a
российские войска человек вышел с
Ukrainian flag came out he was killed And you are
украинским флагом вышел его убили И вы
like Why go out slug one resident of
такие Зачем выходить слага один житель
Donetsk who was in those years
Донецка который находился в те года в
Donetsk says one situation look
Донецке говорит одну ситуацию посмотри
look don't look kill look Now
посмотри не посмотри уби посмотри Сейчас
Sixteen year old boy Chubenko killed in Donetsk
Убитый в Донецке шестнадцатилетний
look Now can we also say you
посмотри Сейчас можно мы тоже скажем вы
us constantly let's go let's go
нас постоянно давайте давайте давайте
Speak like this you were in Donetsk in those years
Говори вот так вы находились в те года в
That is, you speak the situation from
Донецке То есть вы говорите ситуацию со
your side but It's strange I had
своей стороны но Странно у меня были
Odnoklassniki who came as
Одноклассники которые приезжали как
refugees from Donetsk And they said like ours
беженцы с Донецка И говорили типа наши
us like that that is Why speak one
нас типа вот то есть Почему говори одну
situation I explain Yes look those people
ситуацию объясняю Да смотри те те люди
from Donetsk who were taken to Russia Yes
из Донецка которых забрали в Россию Да
they won't say a word against Russia those
они ни слова не скажут против России те
who leave for Ukraine they can already
которые выезжают в Украину они уже могут
or to Europe they speak freely my
или в Европу они свободно говорят моя
mother Yes for now
мама Да пока
look While my mother was in Donetsk
смотри Пока моя мама была в Донецке у
she also had this TV channel come from
неё тоже приехал этот телеканал ээ с
Moscow some Yes it's called Star or
Москвы какой-то Да называется звезда или
something he interviewed her she was on the
что вот он брал интервью у неё она на
street just going to the store they were
улице как раз была в магазин шла брали
interviewing them they come up and say so now
интервью подходят и говорят так сейчас
we will talk about how Ukraine is bombing you
мы поговорим о том как вас бомбит
and she she understands that this is nonsense
Украина и она она понимает что это бред
But she is old She is afraid for her
Но Она старенькая Она боится за свою
life They turn on
жизнь Ей включают
the air for her  and she says Yes, Ukraine is bombing us
эфир и она говорит Да нас бомбит Украина
They leave only when in
Они уезжают только когда в шестнадцатом
2016 I moved her to
году я её перевёз в
Europe to Germany We are now living in Germany
Европу в Германию Мы сейчас в Германии
with her only then
живём с ней только тогда
she took a deep breath she
она вздохнула на полную грудь она вот
when she came out I remember there in
когда вышла Я помню вот тамм в
Dusseldorf at the
Дюссельдорфе в
airport she stood up and
аэропорту она такая встала и такая
said wait Andryusha sighed and
говорит подожди Андрюша такая вздохнула
said I am finally free I can
говорит Я наконец-то свободна я могу
say what I think yes she gave an
говорить то что я думаю да она дала
interview to German German
тогда интервью немецким немецкому
television then she told how the
телевидению рассказывала как в страхе
residents of Donetsk live in fear too yes And our
живут жители Донецка тоже да Вот и у нас
teacher is my Yes Klavdiya Petrovna
учительница моя Да Клавдия Петровна
by the way also left Donetsk but
кстати тоже уехала из Донецка но она
now she has left for the Czech Republic to the Czech Republic she also
уехала сейчас в Чехию в Чехию тоже
breathed a sigh of relief
вздохнула свободно
really so what you see here The problem is that
реально так что тут видишь Проблема в
people in the occupied
том что люди на оккупированных
territories cannot speak
территориях не могут говорить
If you are in Stavropol where there is no war You are
Если вы в Ставрополе где нет войны
afraid Well, you understand what will happen to you
Боитесь Ну понимаете что будет с вами
If you simply go out against Putin to
Если вы выйдете просто против Путина
say something Putin is a thief we are not
что-то сказать Путин вор мы не
going to go out no way yes no That's
собираемся выходить не так вот да не Вот
exactly it And in Donetsk no one is going to at all
вот именно А в Донецке вообще никто не
because it is very strict
собирается потому что это очень стро
look you are talking about adults
смотрите вы говорите про взрослых людей
who understand plus or minus let's say yes
которые понимают плюс-минус допустим да
Like your mother what can happen If
Как ваша мама что может произойти Если
she starts telling the truth being in
она начнёт говорить правду будучи в
Donetsk was whose year That is what
Донецке был чей год То есть это какой
class were we that children do not realize this do not
класс мы были что дети этого не осознают
say children no look again again
не гово дети нет смотри ещё раз ещё раз
children look we have all neighbors
детей смотри у нас все соседи
instruct children not to
проинструктировать детей чтобы они
utter a word Yes
ничего не пикнули Да ничего ни за
do not say anything for Poroshenko that only Putin that's
Порошенко не говори что только Путин вот
really because they were afraid because they
реально потому что боялись потому что
went to kindergartens and schools Yes
ходили в садиках и в школах Да
they asked like how do your parents
спрашивали типа как Ваши родители
feel about Putin How do your parents
относятся к Путину Как Ваши родители
feel about Russia yes in
относятся к России да в
what nothing child He has too I'll
что ничего ребёнок У него слишком я тебе
tell you in Donetsk school number three yes in Donetsk school number three
скажу в Донецкой школе номер три да в
yes there was an
Донецкой школе номер три да был
incident they built the whole school Yes and they took out
инцидент построили всю школу Да и вывели
three people who on the questionnaire Yes uh they
трёх человек которые на в анкете Да ээ
wrote that they were not afraid for Ukraine they
написали что они за Украину не побоялись
took them out in front of the whole class they expelled them from
вывели перед всем классом отчислили из
school Yes they sent a sixteen year old to
школы Да шестнадцатилетнего отправили на
correctional labor Shakhty But these
исправительные работы Шахты А вот этих
two fourteen year olds were sent to
четырнадцатилетний двух отправили в
evening school under the supervision of a children's
вечернюю школу под надзором детской
police rooms you know
комнаты милиции понимаешь
And by the way in 1914 in
А у нас кстати в четырнадцатом году в
1915 we had delicious candies
пятнадцатом были вкусные конфеты
Poroshenko
Порошенко
super Listen, how do you feel about the fact
супер Слушай а вот как ты относишься к
that the Russian army destroyed
тому что Российская армия уничтожила
Mariupol destroyed the city of Bakhmut and
Мариуполь уничтожила город бахмут и
destroying other cities I don't care at all Ukraine
уничтожая другие города мне вообще
destroys chickens Belgorod is
всёравно Украина кур уничтожает Белгород
like normal Well, this is Ukraine defending itself, how does
типа норм Ну это Украина защищается как
it defend itself if it also attacks
она защищается если она тоже нападает
no, look, it's very simple, very I'll
нет смотри очень просто очень Я те я
explain to you that
тебе объясню то что
Ukraine is liberating the Kursk region yes,
Украина освобождает курскую область да
then Russia should pull troops from
Россия тогда должна оттягивать войска с
Donbass that's all Well, the
Донбасса вот и
course is Ukrainian territory,
всё Ну курс - это украинская территория
it was Lenin who illegally transferred the course to Russia they
это Ленин незаконно передал курс России
already remembered Lenin Lord No,
было уже Ленина вспомнили Господи Не ну
well, Kursk, look, Kursk has been Ukraine since the times of
ну Курск смотри Курск ещё со времён
Kievan Rus, it was Ukraine, it was subordinate to Kyiv,
Киевской Руси это была Украина он Киеву
look, let's go back to the
смотрите вот Давайте тогда вообще к
very beginning of our conversation You
самому началу нашего разговора Вот вы
initially said that I'm just
изначально сказали то что я просто
talking I don't swear correctly Yes, I do
разговариваю Я не ругаюсь правильно Да я
n't swear I'm
же не ругаюсь Я же
debating That is, you initially
дискутировать То есть вы изначально
Sit down here to debate Yeah, from
Садитесь сюда чтобы дискутировать Угу с
under yourself, that is, in your background  the
пода себя то есть у вас на фоне висит
Ukrainian
украинский
flag is hanging you are for Ukraine
флаг вы за Украину
right Now you are trying to
правильно Вот вы сейчас нам пытаетесь
prove something to us I just don't want to
что доказать Я просто не ничего не хочу
prove anything I want to understand for myself I am
доказать Я хочу для себя понять Я же
asking you in order to
спрашиваю вас для того чтобы больше
understand more in my head I don't want to
понять у себя в голове я не хочу Вас
convince you just And by the way
переубедить просто А
at the
кстати при
same time Speak
этом Говори
as if the feeling is that you are
как бы ощущение такое то что вы
trying to change our opinion we
пытаетесь поменять наше мнение мы
let's say not now we can not We go to
допустим не сейчас можно мы не Заходим в
chat roulette to let's say
чат-рулетку чтобы допустим
somehow discuss with Ukraine and so
подискутировать как-то с Украиной и так
on so if we come across someone
далее вот если нам кто-то попадается
if they are aggressive goodbye if we
если они агрессивные до свидания если мы
communicate we just communicate Here you
общаемся мы просто общаемся Вот вы
initially Go to chat roulette from the
изначально Заходите в чат-рулетку с той
position to discuss and at the same
позиции чтобы подискутировать и при этом
time you are simply now trying to change
всём вы просто сейчас стараетесь менять
our opinion That is, you say and for us it
наше мнение То есть вы говорите а у нас
was like this And what would have happened to you
вот так вот было А что бы вам было бы
if you had come out against Putin and so
если бы там вы против Путина вышли и так
on and so forth Well for what Yes
далее и тому подобное Ну Для чего Да
look and here is another interesting question
смотри а вот ещё интересный такой вопрос
Russia in addition to Ukraine attacked Georgia
Россия кроме Украины нападала на Грузию
so in 2008 remember on August 8
так вот в 2008 году помните 8 августа
Russia attacked Georgia Georgia because of
Россия напала на Грузию на Грузию она
what  attacked Yes, how do we know I don't
из-за чего напала Да мы откуда знаем не
know I was 4 years old in general the
знаю мне было 4 года вообще максимально
strangest question and you and by the way do you remember
странный вопрос а вы а вы кстати помните
Germany attacked Russia
Германия напала на Россию
yes the treaty Yes And why was that in
да договор Да А почему такое было в
what year did Germany attack Russia
каком году Германия напала на Россию
Russia appeared in the ninety-first year
Россия В девяносто первом году появилось
Well USSR A I got it yes Yes a good question
Ну СССР А понял да Да хороший вопрос
Yana I as a history teacher will tell you
яня я как учитель истории вам расскажу
where in the fact that the Soviet Union was an
де в том что Советский Союз был
ally of Germany they attacked
союзником Германии они вместе напали на
Poland together Yes and the Soviet Union grabbed
Польшу Да и Советский Союз отхватил себе
part of Poland and then Germany attacked
часть Польши а потом Германия напала на
Poland more precisely then Germany together with the
Польшу точнее потом Германия вместе с
Soviet Union attacked Poland and
советским союзом напала на Польшу а
then Germany decided to attack the
потом Германия решила ещё напасть на
Soviet Union its ally because
Советский Союз на своего союзника потому
they were you see like that all What like that
что они были видишь такими всё Какими
And by the way how do you feel about the
такими А вот кстати как вы относитесь к
fact that I very often come across
тому То что мне очень часто попадается
videos on Instagram that the
видео в Инстаграме которые выкладывают
Ukrainians themselves post that is they propagandize
сами украинцы то есть они пропагандируют
as their Instagram as the fact that we are for
как свой Instagram как то что вот мы за
Ukraine we are against the war there Let's all
Украину мы против там войны Давайте все
say so from our territory and they
с нашей территории так скажем вот и они
post videos where
выкладывают видео где
they some war songs that is
они какие-то военные песни то есть там
Katyusha for example although their grandfathers died for it That is how do
Катюша например хотя их деды за это
you feel about such
умирали Вот то есть как вы к таким вот
Ukrainians  treat And how do I just
украинцам относитесь А как я просто
Look, I'm uh, originally from the Soviet Union
Смотри я ээ сам с Советского Союза родом
Yes, we also remade the song Katyusha
Да мы тоже песню Катюша переделывали
in childhood back in the Soviet Union
обли в детстве ещё в Советском Союзе
When we lived, look Well, as a child it's
Когда жили смотрите Ну детстве это
a little different, that is, as a child, for
немного иначе то есть в детстве как бы
example, look, we had we sang something like
например смотри у нас было мы пели типа
Apple trees blossomed, toys, shoes floated
Расцветали яблони игруши поплыли башмаки
over the river Katyusha came out to the shore and
над рекой Выходила на берег Катюша и
shot sausage at the Germans, that's what we
стреляла в немцев колбасой вот мы так
said in the context of the fact that all the
говорили в контексте таком то что всё
guys who live in Ukraine Let's
ребята которые живут в Украине Давайте
stop singing these Russian songs I
перестаём петь вот эти вот песни русские
mean, Russian is a Soviet
В смысле русские это Советская а не
song and not a Russian song, Soviet Why bother with words,
русская песня советские Зачем до слов
like, what are we doing now in Russia in general Well,
как бы мы что сейчас в России в общем Ну
not us Well, only we in general let's
не мы Ну только мы в общем давайте
stop Pere Pepes I understand I know
переставать Пере пепес я понял Я знаю
why I do this, look because we in
почему я так де смотри потому что мы в
Ukraine think that these are old songs of a
Украине считаем что это старые песни э
country that no longer exists, the Soviet Union,
страны которой уже нет Советского Союза
even You don't know these songs either,
уже даже Вы тоже же не знаете эти песни
you don't know Katyusha, we know Well,
вы не знаете Катюшу зна знаем А ну
let's all the verses Tell me, let's let's
давайте все куплеты Расскажите мне
go out to the shore no, no, We
давайте давай выходила на берег нет нет
blossomed We blossomed Let's start over We
Расцветали Расцветали Давайте сначала
blossomed  The apple trees and pears were in bloom, the
Расцветали Расцветали яблони и груши
fog floated over the river Katyusha came out on the embankment to the
поплыли туман над рекой Выходила набере
high bank on the steep The
Катюша на высокий берег на крутой
song of the hall came out about the gray-blue one about the one she loved About the one the
Выходила песня зала про сного сизого о
dog
Про того которого любила Про того че пес
protected About the one she loved About the one the dog protected And then on Well, so
берегла Про того которого любила Про
the verses I'm telling you you don't know further
куплеты Я же говорю вы не знаете дальше
lum not you sang the first verses and the chorus That's
люм не вы первый куплеты и припев спели
exactly it You see you don't even appreciate
Вот именно Видишь вы вы даже не Цените
these songs Why do we need them If you don't
эти песни Зачем они нам Если вы не
know them
знаете им
May 9th so look you
9 мая по так смотри ты даже второй
can't even name the second verse You only the
куплет не можешь назвать Ты только
first verse and the chorus I said when
первый куплет и припев Я же сказал при
listening to the song all this is remembered well well well
прослушивании песни это всё вспоминается
tell me dark-skinned girl
на хорошо а ну смуглянку мне скажите
Let's somehow in the morning at dawn Let's
Давайте как-то утром на рассвете Давайте
somehow in the morning at dawn went into the
как-то утром на рассвете заходил
neighboring garden There Dark-skinned
соседний сад Там Смуглянка
Moldavian girl is picking grapes I blush I
молдованка собирает виноград я краснею я
pour and I don't know what to say next I don't
лею и не знаю что сказать дальше я не
remember By the way I just have another version in my head
помню Кстати у меня просто в голове
where
там где
Yes there Dark-skinned Moldavian girl was rubbing her
Да там Смуглянка молдованка потирал
finger you wanted this Yes
пальц ты вот это да хотела
I did  I know, yes, it comes from the USSR, and
Да я ж знаю да это ещё с Совка идёт а
what other Soviet songs do you remember?
какие ещё вы советские песни помните
And this, my God,
А этот господи
now, damn, you say that Ukrainians
Сейчас блин Вот вы говорите что украинцы
on Instagram are around this drawing of a
в Инстаграме вокруг это рисунок
boy He drew it on a piece of paper and
мальчишки Нарисовал он на листке и
signed it in the corner Let there always be
подписал в уголке Пусть всегда будет
sunshine Let there always be sky Let there always be something The sea will
солнце Пусть всегда будет небо Пусть
always be me and
всегда что-то будет море всегда буду я и
something there Let there always be
что-то там Пусть всегда будет
mom, that is, look That is, you yourself don’t
мама то есть смотри То есть вы сами не
know these songs Well, Three Tankers, you
знаете эти песни А ну Три танкиста
know the song Well, maybe I know Sing along
знаете песню Ну за Пойте может знаю
Let’s go Clouds are moving gloomy on the border Let’s go
Давай на границе тучи ходят хмур Давай
further I don’t remember Well, that is, in any case,
дальше Не помн ну то есть в любом случае
we know them These are not some kind of look Look,
мы их знаем это не какие-то смотри
you say that, uh, Ukrainians on
смотри вы вы говорите что ээ украинцы в
Instagram are saying why do we need these
Инстаграме говорят зачем нам эти
Soviet songs So you yourself don’t know
советские песни Так вы сами не знаете
these songs Ukrainians know more We say
эти песни украинцы Больше знают говорим
Why do we need these Soviet songs, and on the contrary,
Зачем нам эти советские песни а наоборот
when they play, we try to sing along
когда они играют мы стараемся подпевать
as much as We know or don’t know, and
насколько Знаем мы или не знаем а
Ukrainians at the moment are now saying that
украинцы на данный момент сейчас говорят
this is complete nonsense Sing these songs
то что это полная по не Пойте эти песни
because it belongs more to
потому что это принадлежит больше к
Russia Why is that So you look You yourself do
России Зачем так Так вы смотри вы сами
n’t know these songs Why do you Ukrainians need  you
не знаете этих песен зачем вы украинцам
are telling something we want to sing new
что-то рассказываете Мы хотим петь новые
songs in Ukrainian so so
песни украински так так
sing your position Kai that's all then if
Пойте свою позицию Каю Всё тогда если
our Ukrainians say let's not
наши украинцы говорят Давайте не будем
sing Russian these songs are Soviet Yes
петь русские эти песни советские Да
what difference does it make to you what the
какая вам разница что будут петь
Ukrainians will sing And what difference does it make to you what will
украинцы А какая вам разница что с нами
happen to us if we go out with a poster that
будет если мы выйдем с плакатом то что
we are against our president are also
мы против нашего президента тоже
interesting you They attacked us I explained to you
интересны вы На нас напали Я же тебе
In short you They attacked us we attacked you we
Короче вы На нас напали мы на вас
are sitting at home look here is your
нападали мы сидим дома смотри вот твоя
girlfriend Yes she said that I want to
подружка Да говорила что я хочу вас
convince you I do not set myself the goal of
переубедить Я не ставлю себе целью вас
convincing you because in order to
переубедить потому что чтобы кого-то
convince someone they need to have
переубедить нужно чтобы у него были
certain cognitive
определённые когнитивные
abilities Tell me please are you
способности Скажите пожалуйста вы ведёте
streaming I already told you and we yes you
Стрим Я же тебе уже говорил а мы да вы
record me yes No of course damn I do
меня записываете да Нет конечно блин я
n't want to see myself on TikTok later
не хочу потом себя в тиктоке
now no we are not recording anything
сейчас нет мы ничего не записываем
and which ones Listen and which Soviet
а каких Слушайте а каких вы советских
poets do you
поэтов
know Soviet poets I don't like
знаете советских поэтов Я не люблю
quiet writers
тихи а писателей
Soviet writers I don't like reading
советских писателей Я не люблю чить
books Mayakovsky which of  Mayakovsky you
книги Маяковский что из Маяковского вы
know Akhmatova And on Akhmatova Sovetskaya
знаете Ахматова А на Ахматова Советская
yes
да
me about
меня пра
such a question for you yes that's how you
такие вопросик вам да вот вы так
say that you are Soviet songs you are a
говорите что вы песни советские вы там
veteran of the war there Yes you love May 9 Yes
тите ветераном война Да 9 мая любите Да
it's my favorite holiday children super yes
это мой любимый праздник дет супер да
can you tell me when the Great
можете сказать когда началась Великая
Patriotic
Отечественная
War began July 24, 1941 24
война 24 июля 1941 года 24
and that's right forty-first year so uh
и правильно сорок первого года так ээ
patriotic great Patriotic or
отечественна велико Отечественная или
just the Second World great
просто Вторая мировая велико
Patriotic 1941 Yes but not 24 but June 22
Отечественная 1941 Да но не 24 а 22 июня
well yes I thought either 22 or and the first
ну да я думала либо 22 либо а первая
world oh The Second World War when it
мировая ой Вторая мировая война когда
began in
началась в
1939 what date
1939 какого числа
oh in May in my opinion no that's right in May Yes
о в мае по-моему нет правильно в мае Да
May 2 is right and it ended on September 1
2 мая правильно а закончилось 1 сентября
thirty-ninth year yes the second
тридцать девятого года да второ
good and how so who let's say who
хорошо а как вот кто скажем так кто
created the
создал
USSR you asked I don't know Well this is
СССР это вы просил Я не знаю Ну это же
our history our Soviet history
наша история наша Советская история деды
our grandfathers Who created the USSR this well to be honest
наши Кто создал ССР это ну честно говоря
let's say something I know from the collapse of the
допустим что-то я знаю от распада
Soviet Union But how all this
Советского Союза Но как это всё
was created I well who shot who
создавалось я да ну кто кто расстрелял
tsar who invented Ukraine well to be
царя кто кто придумал Украину
honest I don't really like
ну честно говоря я не очень люблю
history because it's been rewritten 10,000 times
историю потому что она 10.000 раз
and we don't know how it
переписана и мы не знаем как это было на
really was I'm not interested in it in principle
самом деле мне в принципе неинтересно
so Well in general it's interesting to study
поэтому Ну вообще интересно изучать
I You don't honor your grandfathers history and you
я Вы не чтите своих дедов историю а
tell the Ukrainians that they don't
украинцам говорите что они песни не
want to
хотят
listen to songs What does it have to do with honoring and the fact that
слушать Причём здесь чтим и то что
history can be rewritten I got it
история может быть переписана
Let's say the beginning of the war that is this
понял Вот я допустим начало войны то
June 22 I remembered only
есть вот это 22 июня я вспоминала только
because I was in a patriotic
потому что я была в патриотическом
camp and on June 22 we woke up at 4:00 in the
лагере и мы 22 июня просыпать в 4:00
morning and marched on the parade ground That's why
утра и маршировали на плацу Вот поэтому
I remembered And why did we march on the parade ground
я запомнила А зачем маршировали на плацу
Well that is we got up at 4 in the morning
Ну то есть мы в 4 утра встали
to mark That is how all the soldiers at
промаркировать То есть как все солдаты в
that time
то время
got up to honor their memory and
поднялись чтобы почтить их память и и
marched
маршировали
cool interesting Fun And what kind of
прикольно интересная Забава А что за
patriotic camp was it I e Honestly I
патриотический лагерь это был я е Честно
don't remember the name anymore I was 12 I already
Уже не помню название мне было 12 я уже
forgot I got it
забыла понял
Pioneer compressed was the one who pestered
Пионер сжатый был который приставал
pestered Yes there was Pioneer compressed who
приставал Да был Пионер сжатый который
pestered No there wasn't  already
приставал Нет не было уже
Pioneers camp counselor and but no everything
Пионеров вожатый в лагере и но нет всё
was calm Understand Yes Listen and here from
было спокойно Поня Да Слушай а вот из
our grandfathers on which front did your grandfather
наших дедов ваш Дед на каком фронте
fight By the way I found out this
воевал Вот кстати я это узнавала
let's say from my grandmother that is from
допустим у бабушки то есть у
her Well she found out from my father and when my
её Ну вот она узнавала у отца и когда
father brought her back from the war that is mine he
отец прил её с войны то есть мой он
said that I won't tell you anything at all it's a
сказал то что я вам вообще ничего
terrible time
рассказывать не буду это страшное время
I don't want to remember it that is logical that
я не хочу это вспоминать то есть логично
my great-grandfather met my
то что мой прадед познакомился с моей
great-great-grandmother already being after That is it
пра прабабка уже будучи после То есть
turns out your great-grandfather could not have fought and
получается твой прадед мог не воевать а
could have been a traitor So why not in
мог быть в предателях Так почему нет в
any case so he had
любом случае так медали у него остались
stolen medals maybe well and where did he fight where
ворованные может ну а где он воевал где
Well maybe stolen to be honest I didn't
Ну может ворованный если честно меня
understand this question at all honor Tish
вообще не этот вопрос понял чти Тишь
Veteranov but you are not your great-grandfather a veteran
Ветеранов но тебя не твой прадед ветеран
yes Question like like just to the words Yes
да Вопрос как типа вот просто до слов Да
very much I have for example my great-grandfather I don't
очень у меня вот допустим прадед я не
know how exactly he fought
знаю как там именно что воевал потому
because my grandmother once told me but I
что мне как-то бабушка рассказывала но я
don't remember all the details I know that
не помню все подробности я знаю то что
he fought under the
он воевал под
command of Zhukov Zhukov  Zhukovsky
командованием Жукова Жуков Жуковский
Zhukovsky Yes they reached
Жуковского Да они дошли до
Berlin he had many wounds
Берлина у него было много ранений
especially there were fragments near the heart or
особенно были осколки возле сердца то ли
I think about 12 pieces were pulled out but three fragments
по-моему штук 12 вытащили но три осколка
remained Until the end of his life and he died
остались До конца его жизни и он умер
by the way relatively not so long ago only
кстати относительно не так давно только
in 2010 and he himself is My grandfather is
в 2010 году вот а сам это Дед у меня
Ukrainian my grandmother is
украинец бабушка у меня
Belarusian that's how it is and you
белоруска вот так вот а ты какая-то
turned out to be some kind of hybrid yes And I am a hybrid I am the USSR My
гибрид получился да А я гибрид Я СССР
mother is Russian my mother is Ukrainian not my
Мама у меня русская мама украинка не
dad is Ukrainian my mother is Belarusian yes And you are a
папа украинец мама белорусска да А ты
Hybrid no And my mother is Russian my father is Ukrainian Well so your mother is
Гибрид нет А мама у меня русская отец
Russian my
украинец Ну по так мама у тебя русская
father is Ukrainian and my grandmother is
отец украинец а бабушка
Belarusian Yes it's some kind of
белорусска Да это какая-то мутация
interesting mutation Yes I am the
интересная Да я есть
USSR And how is USSR deciphered and the Union of
СССР А как расшифровывается СССР а Союз
Socialist Union Union of Soviet
Социалистических Союз Союз Советских
Socialist Republics no slightly
Социалистических Республик нет чуть-чуть
wrong Union of Soviet Socialist
не так Союз Советских Социалистических
Union of Socialist Soviet
Союз Социалистических советских
Republics She
республик Она правильно
said it right and how is RSFSR deciphered
сказала а как расшифровывается РСФСР
rfss Union of Soviet Socialist
рфсс Союз Советских Социалистических
Republics Yes I checked you that's how I
Республик Да я тебя проверял это я так
trolled tro well And what was it
потроллил тро хорошо А какая была
capital of the
столица
USSR Moscow No, this was the capital of Russia
СССР Москва Нет это России столица была
And the USSR had Moscow USSR
Москва А у СССР Москва СССР
Saint Petersburg Leningrad that's right
санкт-петербург Ленинград правильно
Saint Petersburg
санкт-петербург
Ngrad Lenin was from the USSR he invented the
нград Ленин ж был из СССР он придумал
USSR and Leningrad - It was the capital of the USSR
СССР и Ленинград - Это была столица СССР
and Stalingrad was given to Stalin Yes Stalingrad was
а Сталинград Сталину отдали Да
given to Stalin And listen,
Сталинград это Сталину отдали А слушай а
in what year did Lenin come up with the
в каком году Ленин придумал
USSR he came up with the USSR he sat and
СССР придумал сидел и
thought I don't know
думал не знаю
but the RSFSR existed from 1918 to 199 you
вот РСФСР существовала с 1918 по 199
read this you read yes Well yes I
читаешь это ты читаешь да Ну да я
initially said I'm in history, let's say
изначально сказала я в истории допустим
not to the end RSFSR Russian Soviet
не до конца РСФСР Российская Советская
Federative Socialist Ok and
Федеративная Социалистическая хорошо а
what do you think Why did Napoleon oppose
как ты считаешь Почему Наполеон выступал
Lenin I don't know history I don't know anything about it
Ленина Я в истории не шарю я никак нече
and created the USSR Why did Napoleon
ипе и создавал СССР Почему Наполеон
attack Russia like Lenin didn't
нападал на Россию типа на Ленина не
want the creation of the USSR Why was he afraid maybe he was afraid of what he was
хотел создания СССР Почему боялся может
from France what was he
быть боялся чего он из Франции че он
afraid of the
боялся
SSR that it would become even bigger and attack that's
ССР то что она станет ещё больше и напад
right Yes because Napoleon had a
правильно Да потому что у Наполеона было
demand not to Urup USSR yes because
требование не Уруп СССР да потому что
it can un
оно может ун
Napoleon and the
Наполеона и
USSR I  now on the lake on the
СССР я сечас на озере на
lake Ice
озере
Ice Battle on the Ice Battle on the Ice I
Ледо Ледо Ледовое побоище ледовое
remembered my classmate and Yes why is the
побо одногрупницу вспомнила а Да почему
battle between Napoleon and Lenin called the
битва Наполеона с Лениным называется
Battle on the Ice Well because it probably
побоище Ну потому что наверное она
took place in winter and everyone was frozen and everyone
проходило зимой и все замёрзли и всем
felt bad because on the ice of the lake it was on the ice of
было плохо потому что на льду озера она
what
льду какого
lake Ice No well ice because the lake was frozen And on what
озеро замёрзло А на каком озере
frozen lake did it take place Issyk-Kul in
замёрзшем проходила иссыкуль в
Kyrgyzstan and Kul in Kyrgyzstan we'll
Кыргызстане и Куль в Кыргызстане
remember I understand And you at school like well you
запомним понял А вы в школе типа ну ты
know history more or less normally there
нормально более-менее историю знаешь там
no worse than your
не хуже чем
peers and you know mathematics well
одногодки а математику хорошо
no with will be 1% of 100
нет с будет 1% от 100
rubles we said
руб мы сказали
no
нет 100 руб правильно 1% от 100 руб
100 rubles correct 1% of 100
остаётся 100 руб правильно а 10% от 100
rubles there are 100 rubles left correct and 10% of 100 rubles How much is 10 rubles no Well look
руб Сколько будет 10 руб не Ну смотри
if 1% of 100 rubles is 100 rubles then 10%
если 1% от 100 руб - это 100 руб то 10%
is 10 times more then how much will 10%
это в 10 раз больше то сколько будет 10%
of  100
от 100
rubles I don't know 90 rubles is correct and how much
руб не знаю 90 руб правильно а сколько
is 100% of 100 rubles but rubles is correct and
будет 100% от 100 руб но руб правильно а
200% of 100 rubles How much is Minus 100
200% от 100 руб Сколько будет Минус 100
rubles is correct Well that's it Mathematics - it's
руб правильно Ну всё Математика - это
all just helped it's not clear I understand no no
всё просто помогли непонятно Поня не не
need mathematics but loved geography I
надо математику а географию любили Я
really loved geography at school I had a
очень любил географию в школе у меня был
very bad teacher at
очень плохой учитель в
school I got
школе
stuck developed lessons about got stuck yeah
зависла развила уроки про зависла да
like no not stuck here I'm looking yeah And what
типа не не зависла тут смотрю да А какой
subject were you interested in at school
предмет интересн тебе был в школе
I Well you both
мне Ну вам обоим
recess Russian literature liked
перемена русския литература нравились
How many letters are in the Russian
Сколько букв в русском
language 32 303 why such
языке 32 303 зачем такие
questions how much is 32 or 33 33 you gu And
вопросы сколько то 32 или 33 33 вы гу А
how many sounds are there in the Russian language you
сколько звуков в русском языке вы
google there yeah Yes not necessarily I'm
гуглите там да Да не обязательно я же
just a teacher of the Russian
всего лишь учитель русского
language And how many cases are there in the Russian language nominative genitive dative
языка А сколько падежей в русском языке
instrumental
творительный
nominative prepositional and
именительный предложный и
seventh dative you said dative and
седьмой дательный ты сказала дательный и
seventh
седьмой
after genitive
после родительный
instrumental blame accusative
творительный вини винительный
prepositional also address when they address
предложный ещё обращай когда обращаются
there  old man Father Well, we didn't
там старче Отче А ну это у нас такого не
have that in the program, like Pushkin there What do
было в программе вот как Пушкин там Что
you need old man the goldfish
тебе надобно старче рыбка золотая
said we didn't have that in the
говорила у нас такого не было в
program When we were already learning Russian now
программе Когда мы уже учили ру сейчас
it's not in the Russian
этого нет в программе русского
language program now there's a new new part of speech
языка сейчас есть новый новая часть речи
called sensory
которая называется чувственная
something there
что-то там
that shows sensations it's a very
которые показывает ощущения это очень
strange part of
странная часть
speech it's like an adverb and very
речи она похожа на наречие и очень
often very often here What do
сильно часто тут очень сильно часто Как
you think How many
вы считаете Сколько приблизительно
Russian soldiers have died in this
российских солдат уже погибло на этой
war approximately I don't know now damn such questions There
войне Не знаю сечас блин такие вопросы
were interesting ones about school why
Интересные были про школу зачем вот
come back again we don't
возвращаться мы не
know about this with
знаем об этом с
each person has their own
у каждого человека есть сво собственное
political You have your
политическое ние У вас есть сво
own political opinion
собственное политическое мнение У
Each person has an opinion that
каждого человека есть
few people want to divulge
о с которое мало кто хочет разглашать
maybe
може
[music] to teach that's
[музыка]
all
вчить вот и всё
good What do you think you'll be a
хорошо Как вы считаете будете вз
teacher and
педагогом а
you I want to be a
вы Я хочу тоже
teacher too that's how we love children I
педагогом вот так вот мы любим детей я
was in a camp counselor near Donetsk
вот была в лагере вожатый у Донецка
Lugansk you you love children but
Луганска вы вы любите детей но
support the killing of
поддержите убийство
people yes that's how you formulate words
людей да то как вы формулирует слова
Apparently yes apparently that's our
Видимо да видимо вот такое вот у нас к
opinion unfortunately I was  the leader of the
сожалению мнение Я была вожатой у
delegation of Donetsk and Lugansk have wonderful
делегации Донецка и Луганска прекрасные
children wonderful children but the
дети прекрасные дети но
leaders Yeah, okay, thank you very
вожатые Да ну ладно спасибо очень
much please don't
приятно пожалуста можете не
thank me By the way
благодарить Кстати
why here's the face of all these Russian
почему вот вам лицо российских этих всех
girls everyone who oh They're there yes yes they're there
девушек все кто ой Они там да да они там
normal normal Here
нормальные нормальные Вот
I'm against the war but I support dry rations for the
Я против войны но я поддерживаю сухпайки
soldiers I carry these are our guys And so
солдатам таскаю это же наши ребята И так
on and so forth and all this red tape
дальше и вся вот эта тягомотина
here's the
вот вам
face of Russia like squeak
лицо России лайк писка
comment letter to my Ista I don't know why it's for
комент пись на мий Иста Я не знаю для
you why you're there to watch on my
чого це тоб для чого тоб там дивитись на
face But for you it's ond T
оцей мий фейс Але для тебе це онд Т
click But you try me and I'll be KTA Wow I have
клика Але ты тримае мене и я буду КТА
a bunch of fouls and I'll have a
Вау в мене там Купа фолов и в мене буде
great mood to do something new cool
класный настрий чтоб робити нове крут
video letter to my Instagram Popik Andriy
видео пись на мий Instagram Попик Андрий
ok Come on I'll
отак Давай я
chka a
чка а